# 网友朋友们在家自己能操作的
This is something our online friends can make at home.
# 手抓饼
Flaky scallion pancake
# 中筋面粉不要太高筋
All purpose flour, not high gluten flour (strong flour).
# 太高筋烙出来手抓饼
Pancake made from high gluten flour
# 出来之后比较硬
Would be too tough to eat.
# 面里边放一点盐
Adding a little bit salt in the flour
# 是让这个面更加有筋性
to produce more gluten.
# 大概一斤面粉六两水
Roughly 6 Liang(300g) water in half kg flour
# 是温水还是 温水
Should be warm water or? warm water.
# 我们给它稍微往里边放点大油
We need to add some lard in it.
# 这样这面会更酥 搁大油是起酥的
This way can make the dough more crispy, adding lard is for crusted top purpose.
# 你看这面水放进去之后
Look, after I put the water in this dough,
# 我们就是充分给它揉 充分的揉开
We are going to fully knead the dough. Fully kneading the dough.
# 里边不要有这种生面 滋润了
We don’t want raw flour in the dough. Moist and supple.
# 揉滋润了之后给它摔一下
After kneading the dough smoothly, slam(bang) the dough a little bit.
# 把面的筋性充分摔出来
Slamming the gluten out of the dough.
# 大爷你瞧
Take a look at Da Ye.
# 从他的手法一看就非常熟悉
His technique is very familiar.
# 是干面点的
Pastry chef indeed.
# 搁盆里饧个十五分钟 很快
Leave in the pot for 15 mins, very quick.
# 看这盆多干净
Look how clean the pot is.
# 师父咱们这个面饧着的时候
Master, while our dough is resting,
# 我们给它切一点点香葱
We chop some scallions  for it.
# 香葱最好就用葱叶
I prefer to use leaves.
# 这时候师父大爷您看
When you are looking at it this time, Master and Da Ye
# 我这儿准备了两款油
I prepared two types of oil.
# 这是猪大油 这是黄油
This is lard and this is butter.
# 加完黄油之后手抓饼会更香
Adding butter will give our pancake more aroma.
# 有一种奶油的味道 而且还酥脆
It will have a taste of cream and crispy.
# 把猪大油融化一下
Let’s melting the lard.
# 黄油 黄油和猪油一半一半 可以了
Butter, 50% butter and 50% lard. OK.
# 主要是把它融化 加点温度之后
It’s just to melt it. After warming it up,
# 我们把葱花给它倒进去
We add scallions into the mix.
# 倒进去之后不用使劲的煸炒
It doesn’t require lots of stir-frying after you put them in.
# 关火就可以了
It’s okay to turn it off.
# 让它自然的就降温了
Let it cool down naturally.
# 您看这香味马上就出来了
Look, the aroma is now spreading out.
# 这会我们把它倒到这个小碗里
Now we can pour it in this small bowl.
# 大爷您看这个饧好的面
Da Ye, look at this dough.
# 可以给个特写
Give it a close-up shot.
# 您看一拉它非常滋润了
You can tell how moist and suppl it is when you pull the dough.
# 表面非常光滑了
The surface is very smooth and glow.
# 稍微来点薄面
Let spread some raw flour.
# 我们把它拿出来之后
After we take it out,
# 稍微按一下 不要再揉了
Just gently punch down the dough, no more kneading.
# 因为本身这个面 饧是什么意思
Because of this dough itself, what does ‘resting’ mean?
# 就是让它懈劲 懈筋性
Resting means letting it slacking, losing its gluten.
# 那么你要再揉 它筋性又起来了
If you kneaded it more, more gluten would be produced in the dough.
# 所以就没有意义了
Hence, it is meaningless.
# 所以为什么我问这个问题
So, why I ask this question?
# 让我们网友要知道这个环节
I want to let our online audiences understand this step.
# 因为有网友说我这面和的挺软的
As some audience says that ‘I made dough very soft,
# 怎么一烙出这饼又硬了呢
But after I pan-fry the pancake, it turns to be stiff.’
# 他二次又和了
Because he/she knead the dough twice,
# 所以二次大家不要再和了
Therefore, guys, do not knead the dough at the second time.
# 饧好了就直接用
After the dough is rested, just use it directly.
# 大爷您看我这面擀开之后
Da Ye, look at the dough I rolled out.
# 不用擀的太薄
No need to roll it into a very thin piece.
# 稍微有点厚度就行
A little bit thick is okay.
# 这时候我们稍微往上撒一点盐
Now we spread some salt on top of it.
# 如果家里边有花椒盐也行
If you have, pepper salt is okay as well.
# 你要不加其它东西它也有底味 也香
There is no need to add other stuff. It has base taste. Taste and smells good.
# 你要是面一点味道没有就不行了
It’s not okay if the dough doesn’t have any base taste from the wheat and flour.
# 您看刚才我们炸的油
Check the mix of the oil we fired just now.
# 这时候我们给它刷上去
We can brush it on top of it.
# 这饼一看就好吃
The pancake looks delicious.
# 我们再稍微往上撒一点干面
We add more raw flour on top.
# 可以给它折一下 再给它弄开
And we fold it, and open it.
# 这样也行
It’ll do as well.
# 折一下弄开
Fold and open.
# 然后我们给它剌开 剌成小细条
Then we slice it into small thin dough stick.
# 别剌断 你剌断了也行
Don’t slice completely, it’ll work if you slice it completely.
# 就是不剌断这样好操作一点
It’s easier to process if you don’t slice them completely.
# 得 剌开之后 我们给它卷一下
De (local modal particle of Beijing area), after we slice it, we can roll it up.
# 不要怕油出来
Don't be afraid if oil is spreading out.
# 因为我们刚放干面了 不要怕油出来
Because of the raw flour we spread, don’t worry about the oil.
# 弄成之后我们给它稍微抻一下
After we shaped it, we can hand-pull it a little bit.
# 中间剌一刀 出俩
Slicing it in the middle gives us two pieces.
# 把这抻一抻 越抻越细 成了抻面了
More hand-pulled, thinner and it would turn into hand-pulled noodles.
# 有富余的油咱们再给它刷上点
Brushing some extra oil if more oil left.
# 它要不酥太怪呢
Will be weird if the pancake is not crispy.
# 您看这么抻完了之后
After hand-pulled the dough,
# 我们进行一下盘卷
We can start coiling it up,
# 咱们从一边盘也行 从两边一块盘也行
We can coil it from one side or both sides.
# 那么边上都有死面子你给切掉一点
Can you cut off the unleavened dough on sides if any?
# 两边一块盘也行 咱们就两边一块盘吧
Coiling it up from both sides. Let’s do it in this way.
# 两边盘 盘完之后给它摞上
Coiling up from both sides, and after that just pile it up.
# 这饼 绝了
This pancake is fantastic.
# 两个咱们就给它饧上了
Resting both.
# 饧多长时间 也得饧个八到十分钟
How long? At least 8 to 10 mins.
# 让它把劲儿懈一懈 咱们好往薄了擀
Let it slack and lose the gluten inside so we can roll it out into a thinner circle.
# 大爷您看我们这饼 饧好了
Da Ye, check out the dough. Rested already.
# 我们在外边摊儿上吃
When we are having scallion pancakes outside,
# 好多都不用擀的 直接用手
Most of the pancake are madding by hand only, they don’t roll it out by rolling pin.
# 没问题
No problems.
# 提溜过来 盖上盖儿
Pull it here and cover with lid.
# 这个饼因为熟的很快
As flaky scallion pancake is easy to be cooked,
# 所以说这个火不用给它太小 中火
It’s not necessary to use low temperature, moderate heat will do.
# 你看你大爷
Check out Da Ye.
# 专心致志 看着亮子
He is concentrating on looking at Liang Zi.
# 他亮我也亮
He sparkles and I will too. (It’s a pun. Liang means light, sparkle and bright in Mandarin)
# 咱们给它掀盖儿 看一看
Let’s open the lid and look.
# 因为煎锅它是一面有温度
As the pan will keep the heat inside,
# 所以说咱们经常翻着点 来吧
We’d better flip our pancake more often. Let’s do it.
# 看着就酥脆
It looks crispy.
# 咱们给它稍微刷点油
We can brush some more oil on top.
# 㸆上了 这一下就好了就齐了
Simmer and get concentration (a Chinese cooking method, after the dish is cooked, use low heat to cook it more time until the juice is locked inside or the juicy is getting richer.) It cooked now.
# 大爷香啊 真香
Smells so good. Da Ye. So good.
# 来 咱们起锅
OK! Let’s turn off the heat and it’s ready to serve.
# 为了保险起见 咱们看看
For the sake of assurance, let’s check.
# 这边行是吧 翻一下看看 可以啊
This side, right? Flip it. Nice.
# 再嘘一下 把那面再嘘嘘
Steam it a little bit, and steam that side. (Chinese cooking method, use steam to cook the dough food after turning off the heat)
# 齐活 出锅
Well done! Take it out!
# 你看讲究 这还有吸油纸
Look how fussy I am, oil-absorbing sheet is prepared.
# 咱们稍微给它蓬松蓬松 太酥了
We can gently make if fluffier, too crispy.
# 拖到盘上 一条一条的全开了
Pull it on the plate, each flake of pastry is unfolding from the pancake.
# 齐了 太好了
Perfect, wonderful!
# 完美呈现
Splendid!
# 焦你亮手抓饼 教你把饼亮起来
Jiao Ni Liang flaky pancake, show you how to make your pancake flaky and sparkle.(Another pun)
# 每次都是人家二伯给我吃
Er Bai feed me every time.
# 二伯
Er Bai
# 真是手抓了
This is the real grasp flaky pancake. (It’s a pun. It named as Hand-grasped-pancake in Chinese)
# 大爷 师父
Da Ye and Master.
# 你先尝尝就知道了
Taste it first and you will know.
# 你看好吃 我们评的对不对
It’s tasty. Right?
# 酥脆 绵软 葱香 油香 嫩香
Crispy, Soft inside, Rich aroma of scallion and oil, tender.
shift forward 00:06:14,240
# 我们哥俩走到一起
Two brothers support each other
# 我觉得特别难得
but once in our lives.
# 其实我们小语姑娘
Actually Xiao Yu
# 主要是为网友
is to assist our online audiences.
# 在评论当中
In the comments,
# 网友提出了很多一些疑问
Online audiences ask some questions,
# 她把网友的这些疑问
Xiao Yu gathers these questions,
# 都统计出来
and count them.
# 让咱们
So we can
# 就统一的给网友一个回答
Provide answers to our online audiences.
# 其实很多时候她挺不容易的
In fact, it’s not a easy job for her.
# 有时候两三点钟夜里边她还在工作
Sometimes, she needs to work until 2 or 3 o’clock.
# 是吧
Am I right?
# 这我一定要拍下来
I got to film it.
# 网友们
My friends,
# 多多支持小语工作
Please support Xiao Yu’s work.
# 我们哥俩走到一起
Two brothers support each other
# 我觉得特别难得
but once in our lives.
# 共同的兴趣爱好 互相的信任
(We have) common hobbits, we trust each other
# 互谅互让
We show understanding and sympathy for each other.
# 谦虚谨慎
Prudence and modesty.
# 最重要的还是什么大爷
Da Ye, the most important thing is
# 你知道吗
Do you know?
# 我们俩性格相同
We have similar personality.
# 而且还有什么共同的
Is there anything else we have in common?
# 工作经历
Working experience.
# 共同的梦想
Same dreams.
# 因为这个东西
Because of these.
# 你比如说有一个说着话
There is a saying,
# 叫什么呀
what saying?
# 对等
Equals.
# 这人的能量是吧
It’s the energy of human beings.
# 知识他得基本的对等
Equal understanding of knowledge.
# 这样在一个起跑线上
At this starting line,
# 大家还得最重要的是什么
what is the most important thing for everyone? What’s everyone’s opinion?
# 是什么
What?
# 就有一个词叫什么
There is a word.
# 同频共振
Homo-frequency resonance.
# 它的声音出来是和谐的
It develops the same and harmonious frequency of resonance.
# 我觉得一年来吧
I think during this whole year,
# 你说如果我们要没有一个
If we didn’t have
# 共同的想法和愿望
the same thoughts and aspirations
# 我们不可能走这么长时间
It is impossible for us to walk through this long journey together.
# 可能二伯想朝东走
(There might be a situation) Er Bai wants to walk towards east,
# 我可能想朝北走
I might want to walk towards north.
# 可能我们就分道扬镳了
And then, we might just go our separate ways.
# 正因为我们的目标是一样的
Because of the same goal we have,
# 想法是一样的
The same thoughts we have,
# 我的梦想是一样的
The same dream we have,(we can have this journey)
# 我们的初衷是什么
What is our intention?
# 传播的是中华美食
Promote Chinese cuisines.
# 传承的是我们的烹调技艺
Inheriting our cooking skills
# 所以我们有共同的想法共同的目标
Hence, we have the same goal and ideas.
# 而且还有一种共同的担当
And we can address this together.
# 其实大家都付出了很多
In truth, everyone has contributed a lot.
# 是吧
Right?
# 今天早上起8点就来了
We arrived here at 8 am in the morning.
# 你说现在都10点多了
Now it is ten pm.
# 还没拍完
We still haven't finished
# 还有俩菜 拍完了就12点了
There are another two dishes. After that, it will be 12 am.
# 其实有时候我跟大爷说
Sometimes, I told Da Ye that
# 这么大岁数也挺辛苦的
It is hard work for his age.
# 有时候也想放弃
Sometimes, we are thinking of giving up.
# 基本的这么多年
Basically, during these years,
# 40多年的生活经历
During 40 years’ experience,
# 我们完全可以过的挺舒服的生活
We can just live in a comfortable life.
# 你说有时候把自己搞挺累
Sometimes we push ourselves too hard,
# 有时候我也想放弃
I think about giving up as well sometimes.
# 还是是放弃不了
But I just can’t.
# 还是有一种责任的担当
It is a responsibility.
# 肝胆相照
Treating each other with all sincerity.
# 更重要的什么
More important is
# 这个搭档
This partner,
# 比如说
like
# 我再找大爷这么一个搭档
It is too hard to find another partner like Da Ye.
# 太难了
Too hard.
# 二伯就是郭德纲
Er Bai can be Guo De Gang.( well-known Chinese crosstalk comedian)
# 我就是于谦
I can be Yu Qian.( another well-known Chinese crosstalk comedian)
# 不是不是这不是
No, it’s not.
# 这前辈里边 这叫什么啊
How our predecessors call it?
# 过去讲话
In old ways,
# 大家 就侯先生
Mr Hou (a senior Chinese crosstalk comedian)
# 大家
Master.
# 来吧 咱们不扯这个了
Okay, Let’s just stop here.
# 一扯有时候深了容易激动感情
This topic gives us lots of emotional feelings.
# 没有 大家都爱听您聊这些
Not true. We like to hear it.
# 咱们继续
Let’s continue.